<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Es6 on Khoa Pham</title>
    <link>http://khoapham.me/tags/es6/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Es6 on Khoa Pham</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 22:31:31 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://khoapham.me/tags/es6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Webpack Starter - Use ES6 Today</title>
      <link>http://khoapham.me/blog/webpack-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 22:31:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khoapham.me/blog/webpack-starter/</guid>
      <description>Back in early 2015, when I started writing Javascript in ES6; it was not easy to get everything running smoothly at that time. Today some developers are still not sure where to get started using ES6 even though it&amp;rsquo;s widely adopted by Javascript community. I spent an evening writing a simple Webpack Boilerplate to help new developers to use it for their new projects.
What does this minimalist boilerplate include?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ES6 Review Part 2</title>
      <link>http://khoapham.me/blog/es6-review-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khoapham.me/blog/es6-review-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a second review post for new ES6 features that I&amp;rsquo;d love to share. You can find the first review here ES6 Review Part 1
Arrows I have been using arrow (-&amp;gt;) and fat-arrow (=&amp;gt;) key in Coffeescript for while, and I was happy when ES6 would support arrow key (=&amp;gt;) as a short-hand of function keyword. Of course, if you’re familiar with arrow keys in Coffeescript, this feature will be similar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ES6 Review Part 1</title>
      <link>http://khoapham.me/blog/es6-review-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khoapham.me/blog/es6-review-part-1/</guid>
      <description>ECMAScript 6 (ES6) is the upcoming version of ECMACScript standard which is supposed to be ready soon. There are number of significant changes in this new standard version of Javascript. So far I can tell, this is indeed the future of Javascript, and I love it.
In this short blog, I use ES6 to demonstrate some new features of ES6 by writing the linked list data structure.
 Classes ES6 finally allows you to declare your object using class keyword.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>